Lyubomir Ganev

E-mail: luboganev@gmail.com Website: https://luboganev.dev

About me

I am an experienced software engineer focused on native Android development. Through the years I have worked also in other areas of the software development like desktop applications and backend and frontend web development. I am curious and enjoy learning and trying out new technologies while doing some programming during my free time.

Personal Skills & Competences

Software Technologies Programming Languages: Kotlin, Java, Swift.

Frameworks: Android SDK, Bluetooth, BLE, Gradle, Firebase, Fabric, Crashlytics, Sentry, Answers, Play Services, HockeyApp / AppCenter.

Libraries: Ktor, Kotlin multiplatform, Coroutines, Support Library, Android Jetpack, Jeptack Compose, Coil, Lottie, RxJava, RxAndroid, Koin, Dagger, Hilt, Retrofit, Timber, OkHttp, Gson, Moshi, Parceler, Kotlin serialization, Realm, JUnit, Mockito, Mockk, Roboelectric, Espresso.

Web Technologies: HTTP, REST, GraphQL, XML, JSON, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Regex, REST, Markdown, Jekyll.

Version Controlling: Git, Git Flow, GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Stash.

Continuous Integration: Gitlab pipelines, GitHub actions, Jenkins, TeamCity, CircleCl

Databases Technologies: RoomDB, Realm, MySQL, SQLite.

Operating Systems: Mac OS, Android, Windows, Linux.

Programming Environments: Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ Idea, XCode.

Other Competences: Clean, VIPER, MVP, MVVM, Reactive programming, Functional programming, Open Source, Code Reviews, Pair Programming, Stack Overflow, Slack, Scrum, Kanban, Agile, JIRA, Confluence.

Languages

Bulgarian - Native language **English** - Fluent.

German - Fluent.

Work Experience

Jan 2022 - Today | IU International University

Munich, Germany

Senior Android developer

Mar 2019 - Dec 2021 **Automotive startup**

Munich, Germany

Lead Android developer

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019 Luxoft GmbH

Munich, Germany

Technical Lead Android

Sep 2016 - Aug 2018 | **Bragi GmbH**

Munich, Germany

Technical Lead Android

July 2014 - Aug 2016 **Jochen Schweizer Technology Solutions GmbH**

Munich, Germany

Software Developer Mobile

Dec 2013 - June 2014 CHIP Digital GmbH

Munich, Germany

Android Developer

May 2012 - Nov 2013 **1st Position GmbH**

Saarbrücken, Germany

Android Developer

Mar 2011 – Dec 2011 Institut für Wirtschaftsinformatik (IWI) bei DFKI GmbH

Saarbrücken, Germany

Research assistant

Dec 2008 – Oct 2009 | Mobiltel EAD

Sofia, Bulgaria

Web developer

Education

Oct 2009 - Mar 2012

Saarland University

Saarbrücken, Germany

MSc Computer Science

Subjects covered: Database systems, Cryptography, Security, Mobile applications development, Innovative Technologies in Retail Environment, Multi- touch interactions, User interface design and usability

Master Thesis Topic: Framework for Evaluation of Recommender Systems that Suggest Mobile Applications

Oct 2004 - May 2008

Technical University - Sofia

Sofia, Bulgaria

BSc Computer Science

Subjects covered: OOP, Computer networks, Operating systems, Discrete structures, Algorithms synthesis, Computer graphics

References

Publications

AppFunnel: a framework for usage-centric evaluation of recommender systems that suggest mobile applications

Matthias Böhmer, Lyubomir Ganev, Antonio Krüger IUI '13

AppDetox: helping users with mobile app addiction

Lyubomir Ganev, Matthias Böhmer, Markus Löchtefeld MUM '13

Projects

AppDetox

Android application

AppDetox was developed by the AppDocs team which consists of three researchers/ developers including myself. The purpose of the app is to provide heavy Android users with a tool that helps them perform self-control and tame their mobile apps usage on daily basis. Further information available on the official application page in Google Play.

Anidro

Android application

Anidro is a fun app which brings motion to static drawings. Users can create simple drawings on their smartphone or tablet and then share an animated version of these drawings as an animated GIF or video. It is an open-source project which highlights some architectural best practices. Further information available on the official

application page in Google Play and the GitHub page of the project. (http://luboganev.dev/anidro/)

Further projects

For more projects please visit my website. (https://luboganev.dev/about/)